http://www.sdbonline.org/privacy_policy

Menu
About SDBMissionLeadership >Board of DirectorsCommitteesPresident's CornerStaffSDB Past PresidentsPast SDB BoardsPrograms >Boot CampRe-Boot CampChoose Development!PASI Short CoursesScience FestivalsEducation SymposiaSDB HistoryBylawsEducation Programs & InitiativesPosition StatementsPublic Affairs >Public Affairs CommitteePosition StatementsScience Policy IssuesBecome an AdvocateSupport SDBPrivacy PolicyCode of ConductMembershipMembership PortalRenew Join SDBMembership BenefitsMembership TypesMember LinksWhy I Choose DevelopmentIn MemoriamMeetingsSDB 79th Annual Meeting ONLINE >General InformationProgramAbstract SubmissionMeeting RegistrationVirtual Poster SessionsSponsorship and ExhibitorsSatellite SymposiaMeeting App2020 Meeting ReportPast Annual Meeting Posters2020 Mid-Atlantic SDB Regional MeetingSDB Postdoctoral Seminar SeriesAwardsEdwin G. Conklin MedalDevelopmental Biology - SDB Lifetime Achievement AwardViktor Hamburger Outstanding Educator PrizeElizabeth D. Hay New Investigator AwardSDB Trainee Science Communication AwardGrants >SDB Education GrantSDB Meeting GrantSDB Emerging Research Organisms GrantSDB Innovation GrantSDB Puerto Rico Research Relief GrantTravel AwardsJohn Doctor Education PrizeHilde Mangold SymposiumChoose Development!PublicationsDevelopmental Biology >Current IssueSearch IssuesIssues ArchiveSpecial IssuesWIREs Developmental BiologySDB e-newsSDB CoReResourcesSearch ResourcesEducation ResourcesFunding OpportunitiesJob OpportunitiesNewsMember LinksOrganism LinksBooks by SDB MembersGraduate Programs in Developmental Biology >Graduate Programs - AmericasGraduate Programs - AustraliaGraduate Programs - EuropeSocieties
About SDBMissionLeadershipProgramsSDB HistoryBylawsEducation Programs & InitiativesPosition StatementsPublic AffairsSupport SDBPrivacy PolicyCode of Conduct
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy describes how the Society for Developmental Biology (SDB) uses information collected through this website.  SDB may change this policy from time to time by giving users advance notice of the changes and posting an updated version of this policy on this page.  By using this site, you accept and agree to the terms and conditions of this privacy policy.
Collection of Information
In general, this website gathers information about users as a group, such as which areas users visit most frequently and what services users access the most.  This website automatically collects information about user’s IP address, browser, device, operating system, domain name, date and time of access, and general location.
SDB requires users to submit personally identifying information to become a member, order publications, make donations, register for an event, submit an abstract, apply for travel awards, grants or programs, and volunteer.  This information typically includes personally identifying information such as name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, institutional affiliation, academic information, and credit card information.
Credit Card Information
Once your credit card information has been passed to the credit card processing company for verification, only partial information is retained by SDB for future identification of the transaction. This partial information includes the last four digits of the credit card number and card holder’s address when available. We never retain the CVV number. All credit card information is kept within a secure database with limited access by authorized staff.
Cookies
This website uses cookies to maintain user information between visits such as logins. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, so you may accept or decline it.
Use of Information by SDB
SDB uses website data in aggregate to analyze site traffic and determine what is most relevant to users.
SDB uses personally identifying information to complete transactions as requested by users and to make users aware of additional SDB programs, services and products that may be of interest to them.
In general, SDB will retain user information to enforce proper use of this website and for management and administration of SDB’s programs.
Use of Information by Third Parties
If completion of a requested transaction requires sharing information with an outside party, such as a credit card company, SDB endeavors to work only with reputable partners.
SDB provides the name and address of its current members to approved vendors such as publishers, educational institutions, and other scientific vendors through a paid mailing list. Only SDB members who opt in on their membership portal under “Permissions” receive these services.
SDB reserves the right to access, store, and disclose any information that it reasonably considers is necessary to:  (a) meet legal requirements, (b) enforce its terms of use, including investigation of potential violations, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues, (d) respond to user support requests, or (e) protect the rights, property, or safety of the website, its users, and the public.
Except as described above, SDB does not sell, rent, or share the personal information collected through this website.
Please be aware that this website includes applications, advertisements, and links to websites owned by third parties.  This policy does not apply to portions owned by third parties and SDB is not responsible for the practices of third parties.
Accessing Your Information
You may review and edit your account information at any time by logging in to your membership portal. You may update your approval for certain uses by selecting the appropriate box under “Permissions” in your member profile.
Security of Information
SDB uses administrative, physical, and technical safeguards to protect personally identifying information in its records.  Encryption is used to protect sensitive information submitted through this website, such as credit card numbers.  Only employees with a need to know a user’s information are permitted access to personally identifiable information.  The equipment upon which personally identifiable information is stored is kept in a secure environment.
More Information
Questions and concerns regarding this privacy policy can be directed to SDB at sdb@sdbonline.org.
Effective date:  September 27, 2018
Last Updated on 09/27/2018
